<resources>


    <string name="result_description">Thank you for your answers. The number above represents your 10 year risk of
        suffering from a major coronary disease. A result above 5% is considered high and requires medical consultation.
    </string>
    <string name="advice_text">High coronary disease risk is often due to an unhealthy lifestyle. Click below for advice
        about improving it.
    </string>
    <string name="about_text">This application will calculate your 10 year risk of suffering from a coronary disease.
        The calculation is based on Systematic Coronary Risk Evaluation (SCORE) which is the European cardiovascular
        disease risk assessment model.
        For more information about SCORE or more detailed risk evaluation tests you can visit the site of <a
                href="https://www.escardio.org/Education/Practice-Tools/CVD-prevention-toolbox/SCORE-Risk-Charts">
            European Society Of Cardiology</a>.
    </string>
    <string name="cardiovascular_info">Risk Assessments are used to determine the likelihood of patient developing cardiovascular disease, heart attack or stroke in the future.
        In general, patients at higher risk for cardiovascular disease require more intensive treatment to help prevent the development of cardiovascular disease.
        Risk assessments are calculated using a number of factors including age, gender, race, cholesterol and blood pressure levels, diabetes and smoking status and the use of blood pressure-lowering medications.
        Typically, these factors are used to estimate a patient\'s risk of developing cardiovascular disease in the next 10 years.
    </string>
    <string name="diet_info">Diet is vital tool for lowering cholesterol and blood pressure levels, which are two major risk factors for cardiovascular disease.
        Patients with high cholesterol and high blood pressure levels should eat plenty of vegetables, fruits and whole grains and incorporate low-fat dairy products, pultry, fish, legumes, non-tropical vegetable oils and nuts into their diet.
        They should also limit intake of sweets, sugar-sweetened beverages and red meats.
        Patients who need to lower their cholesterol should reduce saturated and trans fat intake.
        Patients with high blood pressure should consume no more than 2,400 mg of sodium a day, ideally reducing sodium intake to 1,500 mg a day.
        In general, adults should engage in aerobic physical activity 3-4 times a week with each session lasting an average of 40 minutes.
        Moderate to vigorous physical activity is recommended to reduce cholesterol levels.
    </string>
    <string name="weight_info">Obesity increases the risk for serious conditions such as cardiovascular disease or diabetes, but losing just a little bit of weight can result in significant health benefits.
        There is no single diet or weight loss program that works best for all patients. In general, reduced caloric intake and a comprehensive lifestyle intervention involving physical activity and behavior modification tailored according to a patient\'s preferences and health status is most successfull.
        Bariatric surgery may be a good option for severely obese patients to reduce their risk of health complications and improve overall health. However, bariatric surgery should be reserved for only the highest risk patients.
    </string>

    <!-- questions for survey -->

    <string-array name="questions">
        <item>What is your sex?</item>
        <item>Do you smoke?</item>
        <item>How old are you?</item>
        <item>What is your systolic blood pressure?</item>
        <item>What is your total cholesterol?</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="question1_answers">
        <item>Female</item>
        <item>Male</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="question2_answers">
        <item>No</item>
        <item>Yes</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="question3_answers">
        <item>40–49</item>
        <item>50–54</item>
        <item>55–59</item>
        <item>60–64</item>
        <item>65+</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="question4_answers">
        <item>less than 140</item>
        <item>140–159</item>
        <item>160–179</item>
        <item>180+</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="question5_answers">
        <item>4,0–4,9 [mmol/l] / 100–149 [mg/dl]</item>
        <item>5,0–5,9 [mmol/l] / 150–199 [mg/dl]</item>
        <item>6,0–6,9 [mmol/l] / 200–249 [mg/dl]</item>
        <item>7,0–7,9 [mmol/l] / 250–299 [mg/dl]</item>
        <item>8,0+ [mmol/l] / 300+ [mg/dl]</item>
        <item>I don\'t know</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="questionsAndAnswers">
        <item>@array/questions</item>
        <item>@array/question1_answers</item>
        <item>@array/question2_answers</item>
        <item>@array/question3_answers</item>
        <item>@array/question4_answers</item>
        <item>@array/question5_answers</item>
    </string-array>


    <string name="startButton_text">Start</string>
    <string name="nextButton_text">Next</string>
    <string name="aboutButton_text">About</string>

    <string name="app_name">Coronary Disease Risk</string>
    <string name="title_activity_result">ResultActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about">AboutActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_question">QuestionActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_info">InfoActivity</string>


</resources>
